Hello. All right. Hello and welcome,
everyone. It is July 11,
2023. We are in active inference
for the social sciences, and today is
going to be a lecture by Ben White on
basics of active inference, the active
inference agent. So, Ben, thank you for
the lecture. Off to you, and we're
looking forward to it. Thank you very
much. Yeah, me too. Very happy to be
a part of this, to be kicking things off
with the first module on this course.
I'm going to be talking about the active
inference agent and trying to cover some
of the basics. I won't take too long
introducing myself. Ava gave a very
thorough introduction in his talk
recently, but I'm a second year PhD
student in philosophy at the University
of Sussex, and I work with Andy Clark
and with Avel and some other people
using active inference to try and find
things out about our relationship with
technology and within the context of
well being and mental health. The aims
for today I'm going to try and provide
quite a wide ranging overview of how
active inference has connected with
areas of philosophical interest, and
particularly how they relate to the
individual agent and the experience of
the agent and how the agent finds
themselves in the world. So I've split
this up to look at several different
defined topics. So I'm going to move
quite quickly through mind, agency,
emotion, and phenomenology, and I'm
going to say a little bit about the self
as well. And then there's going to be a
case study at the end that I'm going to
move through if we have time. So one of
the other aims that I have is to lay out
very clearly some of the core concepts
and core mechanisms like precision,
weighting, and prediction error enactive
models. I'm not going to go into any
technical details whatsoever. This is
all going to be fairly abstract. My
background and my interest in these
frameworks is philosophical, so it's
quite abstract in terms of how
everything fits together. And I'm going
to try and bring some of these threads
together to build up a layered picture
of what the active inference agent is
like, because this course is kind of
aimed towards seeing how active
inference applies to larger scales,
collective behavior, social norms,
sociocultural landscapes. And I think in
order to do justice to those things, we
need to first have a good idea of the
individual in active inference. So we've
got our work cut out for us. So I'll get
started. So before I dive
in, I wanted to just say a little bit
about how these frameworks hang
together. So active inference is
based on Karl Friston's free energy
principle. I think most of us are
familiar with that. But the free energy
principle just states that in order to
persist through time, biological
organisms must occupy only those states
that it would expect to occupy, given
the type of thing that it is so free
energy is essentially a measure of the
disatunment between a system and its
environment. And I'm going to say a
little bit more about attunement and how
that gets cashed out in various ways as
we go on. Active inference is a process
theory that essentially explains how
embodied organisms actually go about
remaining in those expected states. So
how we actually go about minimizing free
energy. And the idea is that all
adaptive behavior is explained by agents
garnering evidence to confirm their own
expectations. Predictive processing.
For the purposes of the lecture today,
I'm going to treat these as synonymous
because most of the work that I kind of
came up through as I was learning about
this was predictive processing. And all
of the papers that we're using today
that refer to predictive processing
refer to a predictive processing that I
take to be more or less synonymous with
active inference. So that's a very
embodied, inactive flavor of predictive
processing. I think generally the
difference is that predictive processing
can be a much broader term and
predictive processing can also apply to
passive models of perception. But we're
not going to concern ourselves with
that. Okay,
so some key concepts of active
inference, predictive processing then.
So the framework says that agents embody
or agents have we won't concern
ourselves with the nuance there, but
they have a generative model, which is
essentially a kind of understanding
or a model of the regularities that
underpin the dynamics between the agent
and the environment. So another way to
think about this in very rough terms is
a kind of mental model of the
regularities in the world and how the
agent exists in the world. And using
that model, the agent can generate
predictions about its own sensory
states. So given the model, what kinds
of sensory states would it expect to
find itself in in a particular set of
circumstances? And so where those
predictions don't actually match the
sensory inputs. So where there's a
discrepancy between the actual incoming
sense data and the prediction,
prediction errors are generated and
prediction errors are going to flow
upwards through the hierarchy. So the
generative model is said to be a
hierarchical model and predictions flow
downwards and prediction errors flow
upwards. And the sole imperative of the
brain body system, according to this
framework is to minimize those
prediction errors.
So a good way to kind of get a
little handle on this is to think about
just the example of perception. So
perception traditionally so I'm talking
about visual perception here. It's
traditionally been understood as a
bottom up process. And what that means
is that the brain waits for incoming
sensory signals and then it processes
them as they come in and it combines
them in kind of increasingly abstract
ways. And what we see is some
combination of those sensory signals
that have come in and been processed and
combined. So if you think about me
leaving my apartment in the morning and
stepping out onto the street and seeing
some cars. What's happening there is
some sensory information is hitting my
retina and it's being processed first
with very basic features like light
shade, edges and so on and so forth.
And then it's being combined with my
understanding of what a car is or what a
bus stop is. And that gives me my kind
of visual field.
Predictive processing, famously at this
point, flips this picture upside down on
its head. So visual perception under
predictive processing is a top down
affair. So the Generative model is going
to encode multilevel expectations about
the likely scene. So, just to be very
clear, when we talk about multilevel and
hierarchical, the higher up levels are
going to be tracking longer timescales
and higher levels of abstraction, and
the lower levels are going to be much
faster and much more concrete. So a
changeable scene, so there's going to be
some variation in what I see when I
leave my apartment every day is going to
mean that there's always going to be
some error in that picture. So it's
never going to be the same two days in a
row or it's extremely unlikely to be.
So no matter how well I can predict what
I'm going to see when I leave my house,
it's always going to be cleaned up by
some prediction errors. So essentially,
when I step outside and I step into the
street, my brain is already anticipating
what it's going to see out there. So I
know where particular cars are going to
be parked, I know where the bus stop is,
so on and so forth. And the perceptual
experience that we have is a
construction. We actually experience the
expectation that has been kind of
cleaned up post prediction error.
There's a little bit of debate there
about exactly what it is that we
experience. But for our purposes today,
we can say that visual perception is
essentially a construction.
So on the face of it, prediction errors
can be minimized using one of two
strategies, and this is going to be
really important.
So we have what I just described there,
which is perceptual inference. That's
where we revise our predictions to
better fit the evidence. So essentially
we update our model to better reflect
the regularities in the environment. Or
we can engage in active inference,
which is where the framework gets its
name from, which is where we essentially
make the evidence fit the model. So
that's where we in some sense update the
world so it conforms to the original
prediction. And active inference agents
bring about those expected states by
sampling the world in a bias way, so
they have certain expectations and then
we sample the world to confirm the
predictions. And I put perceptual
inference there in scare quotes because
perceptual inference on kind of readings
of most readings of active inference
just becomes a kind of action readiness.
Or as Ramstead and colleagues put it, a
state estimation. So it's just
perception and action are just wrapped
up in this continuous loop. But it's
really all about the action. It's really
all about bringing about those expected
states, and perception is just kind of
in service of that process. And so
Bruineberg and colleagues refer to the
enactive inference agent as a crooked
scientist, which is something I really
like. I think that's a very charming
image. So we are scientists that are
engaging in some very dodgy behavior
because we're not really interested in
having an accurate model. We're more
interested in confirming our original
predictions. Okay, so that
was a very rapid overview of some of the
core concepts and mechanisms, but
they're going to crop up continuously.
So I think we're going to get a much
better grasp on them as we go on. In
this section, I'm going to start to
expand on some of those things that
we've just put on the table, and I'm
going to begin to flesh them out in
terms of thinking about how active
inference agents actually exist in the
world. So I should say I
put this here to remind me. So those of
you who are taking part in the course,
I'm going to make available a document
with all of the readings that I firstly,
all of the readings that I've used to
make these slides, and then a bunch of
other readings as well that I think are
going to be very relevant. And
obviously, they're going to be organized
in terms of the structure of this
presentation as well. So this is just
I've put a little sample up on these
slides, but there's going to be much
more in the document. So I think it's
always good to start with some guiding
questions. So I've thrown up three here.
The first is how does enactive inference
characterize cognition? So we've just
looked at predictions and prediction
errors, but we're going to expand on
that a little bit. And we're going to
ask what kinds of processes does
cognition involve? How is cognition
related to the material environment?
This is going to be something how
cognition relates to the environment is
going to be very important in subsequent
weeks. And we're going to ask quite
briefly what kinds of vehicles might
realize cognitive processing.
So here's a couple of whales.
Whales are going to be a recurring theme
in this lecture, but I wanted to take a
step back and ask about Attunement
because this is one of those concepts
that gets thrown around a lot, and I
think once it's grasped, it becomes very
clear and very easy to use. But I think
prior to it being grasped, it can be a
little bit opaque and a bit slippery.
So on the left we have a humpback whale
that was found dead in the Amazon
rainforest, allegedly. I don't know if
this was true. And on the right we have
a whale in its natural environment. And
I think clearly the intuition here is
that in one case the whale is very well
attuned to its environment and in the
other case it's not. And I think that we
can start by asking what is it about the
ocean that allows the whale to be well
attuned? And what I want to say here is
that the particular dynamics between the
ocean and the whale allow the whale to
do certain things that it can't do when
it's in the Amazon. So in other words,
we might say that the ocean affords
certain things to the whale,
specifically filter feeding, being able
to move its vast weight around with
ease, things that, unfortunately, a
whale in the Amazon can't do. So
affordances are opportunities for
action. They are things,
roughly speaking, in the environment
that the agent can act upon. And there's
some debate about the proper way to
really characterize affordances, but I
like to think of them as relational
properties emerging from an
environmental feature and some skilled
embodied ability of the agent. So the
same thing in the environment will not
afford the same thing to different
organisms. So for example,
soil to a human agent might afford
walking on or laying down on, but to an
Earthworm it affords very different
things. And also, even amongst the same
organisms with humans, especially,
different surfaces and features of the
environment will afford different things
depending on your particular skill set.
And agents are going to go about
minimizing their uncertainty, so
minimizing prediction errors, staying
attuned to their environment through an
engagement with affordances. And this is
going to be something that is going to
drift away slightly as we move through
some sections and then it's going to
come back very heavily at the end. And I
should say that the idea of affordances,
to my knowledge, it first emerges in the
work of James Gibson the Ecological
Approach to Visual Perception. I think
it's chapter eight in that book that
really lays out a theory of affordances.
So this idea that systems or
organisms maintain their organization
through ongoing action means that
active inference has been labeled as
quintessentially inactive by Karl
Friston's. And I think that this is a
nice inactivism is an older framework
from theoretical cognitive science and I
think it's a nice way to understand some
of the key features of active inference.
But it does come with a little bit of
historical philosophical baggage. And
I'm going to try and unpack that really
quickly because I want to unpack exactly
what it is that we're committing
ourselves to when we think about
cognition in activist terms.
So inactivism comes in various strands
very, very quickly and roughly, you have
autopoietic inactivism, which commits
itself to what's known as the mind life
continuity thesis. This is essentially
that the structures that give a ground
to life itself are the same structures
that instantiate cognitive processes.
Sensing on this view is teleological
because it's oriented around supporting
vital systems. So things in the
environment have intrinsic meaning to
the organism because they support the
vital functioning of the organism in
some way. Sensory motor in activism
emphasizes how mobile and embodied
agents essentially enact the grounds
and conditions for their own sensory
engagements with the world. So the world
is not a kind of neutral static given
that we're parachuted into actually the
conditions through which we sense the
world are the conditions that we
can move and kind of interact with the
world in various ways and then there's
radical enactivism. And this is the
view that cognition is purely grounded
in these agent environment dynamics.
It's a purely dynamicist account of
cognition and there's no role whatsoever
for internal representations. So
certainly in certain brands of sensory
motor in enactivism there remains a role
for internal manipulation of
representations. And mental
representations are just mental states
that are about something in the world.
So some mental state is reconstructing
some feature of the world. And this all
harks back to kind of old debates in
philosophy of cognitive science between
internalist notions of cognition and
more embodied, embedded, extended and
we'll take more of a look at that in a
second. But the question here is what
are we committing ourselves to with
active inference? And I need to be a
little bit careful because I think that
people are going to disagree with this
to certain extents.
But I think we're certainly committing
ourselves to sensory motor in activism.
I think that's fairly uncontroversial.
And I would say as well that the
underpinning of active inference by the
free energy principle by my lights also
commits us or it certainly chimes very
deeply with the core tenets of
autopoetic inactivism. But I think
what's really interesting in trying to
understand cognition in the active
inference agent is to understand what
role, if any, there are for
representations. So if you
have any familiarity with the literature
on active inference, you'll know that
active inference people are always
banging on about models, prediction
errors, various other computationally
sounding things. And so the worry here
is at least for well, it's not
necessarily a worry, but the thought
would be are we committing ourselves to
a form of cognitivism? And again,
cognitivism is this it's generally
considered to be an old fashioned notion
of cognition as like computation over
symbolic representations in the brain
according to some syntactic set of rules
or something. And typically over the
last couple of decades in cognitive
science people have been moving away
from that view. So it would be
interesting if we were committing
ourselves to something that we'd already
moved away from and some people think
that we are making that commitment. So
Jakob Hohwy, for example, has argued in
various places that essentially
predictive processing or enactive
inference commits us to these very rich
reconstructive notions of
representation. And even Andy Clark,
Jakob Howie's foil in many places
has said himself that he thinks that
representations play a role here as
well. So in a talk in 2016, Clark said
it's internal representation. I think it
is. These are representation using
stories, but it's not internal
representation in quite the way that we
originally thought about it. So there's
some differences, perhaps major
differences between Howie and Clark
there, but others have pushed back. So
there's a paper by Maxwell Ramstead and
colleagues from 2020, I think it's the
tale of two densities paper where they
say that
a proper understanding of the generative
models in active inference suggests that
there's no role for representations. So
this is the kind of anti Howie view.
So I really like this paper from
Avel Constant and Andy Clark and Karl
Friston's which essentially tries to
broker some kind of peace in a debate
that in some form or another has been
raging for decades. So it'd be quite
nice to finally put this to bed.
So they argue that we can find, in the
formalisms of active inference, we can
find grounds for an armistice here.
So they argue that the formalisms of
active inference show that, quote
representational and non
representational cognitive processes can
be implemented by the brain under active
inference. And they do this by showing
that active inference accommodates a
dual architecture. So they show that on
the one hand, in some sense the
brain has to represent because under
active inference action selection
policies are happening over extended
timescales and so the agent has to
engage in some kind of counterfactual
thinking. So if I do X, what happens?
If I do, y what happens? And so on. And
the argument, very roughly speaking, is
that that is going to entail some kind
of representational, some use of
representations. But on the other hand,
they argue that what they call deontic
actions are processed through different
mappings in the generative model and
they're directly triggered by sensory
input. So a deontic action is an action
that is ingrained by our sense of the
expectations of others. So the example
that the authors use is stopping at some
red traffic lights in the middle of the
night when there's nobody else around.
So in a sense the claim is that through
a kind of social conditioning we know
what other people would expect us to do
in those circumstances and that allows
for this kind of dynamic reflexive
action policy setting.
And in those cases there's no room for
representative or there's no need for
representations there. I would
definitely suggest people interested in
this go and read this paper because you
might already have thought of some
potential objections here to the claim
that representations aren't needed for
deontic action and they do go into some
detail in talking about potential
objections there.
So that's the kind of status of the role
of representations. It's a live debate,
not everybody agrees. But it certainly
looks as though active inference has the
formal tools to accommodate both sides
of the debate. And it might turn out
that that's a good thing because we can
make everybody happy or it might turn
out to be a bad thing because you might
think, well, we've not really settled
anything one way or another. I wanted to
take some time, though, to mention
extended active inference. So I've been
talking about inactivism and I've
mentioned this debate between
cognitiveism and older ways of thinking
about sorry, cognitiveism and newer ways
of thinking about cognition as embodied
or embedded. And these are part of
what's known as the four E paradigm.
And clearly I think we are talking about
inactive cognition and you get embodied
and embedded kind of for free with this.
So the only one left on the table is the
extended mind. And this is just the
claim that under some conditions the
system that's realizing
cognitive processing can literally
extend outwards from the mind. So I'll
put some nice read ins for this up if
anybody's unfamiliar and interested.
But it's usually the most controversial
of the four E's. And Andy Clark,
who is one of the original authors of
the extended mind paper, really thinks
that active inference accommodates the
extended mind theory. And it's not just
that it accommodates it, but it actually
solves some old problems in the extended
mind about knowing how and why the brain
knows when and where to recruit certain
extra neural resources. And part of
the argument for this, what really sits
at the core is Clark develops this
argument based on the fact that the
generative models in active inference
are always in this, always making a
trade off between accuracy and
complexity. So you want your model of
the world to be accurate enough that you
can act effectively on the world, but
you also want to minimize the metabolic
costs of having models that are overly
complex. And so Clark utilizes this
insight to make the case that this
explains that in some cases as agents we
make use of these extra neural kind of
props and tools and things. And he says
that the imperative to reduce
uncertainty provides a location neutral
cost function that's always been missing
from the older arguments around extended
mind. So the upshot to
this, I think, is that you end up with a
view of agents as deeply coupled with
their environments. So under active
inference it's just nonsensical to try
and think about agents as decoupled from
their environment. The generative models
themselves are of the dynamics between
the agent and the environment. So these
two things can't be decoupled
perception, action loops. So remember I
said that perceptual and active
inference are essentially the same
thing. They're part of this circular
causality and they see the agent
constantly producing their own worlds.
They occupy the states that they're
expecting to through action.
And we might think, based on the
literature that I've gone through, that
there's some role here for
representations. So we're not committing
ourselves. The active inference agent
is not one that fits with very radical
interpretations of inactivism.
And active inference agents are porous.
They're open to recruiting external
material features of the environment to
reduce complexity and therefore minimize
the metabolic costs of realizing those
expected states.
Okay,
so that was a bit of active inference
set against the backdrop of some older
questions in philosophy of mind
theoretical cognitive science. But I'm
going to jump straight into agency and
motivation now because there's a lot to
get through here. I'm going to start
with a dark room problem. This is a
canonical philosophical worry in active
inference. So a lot of people, I think,
will be familiar with this. And in
really brief terms, it's really easy to
state. The challenge here is to say,
if it's all about minimizing prediction
error, why don't we just find the most
predictable environments possible and
stay there and live a nice error free
life? So Andy Clark paints a picture of
a dark room, and you can just be
strapped up to an intravenous drip,
feeding you the nutrients you need, and
you can just be really happy. But
clearly, we don't do that. Active
inference sorry. Agents in the world,
us, we generally typically sometimes we
do enjoy dark rooms, but most of the
time we don't for any extended period of
time. And so there's a challenge here
about how active inference can account
for what appear to be motivated agential
actions that necessarily mean we're
confronted with some degree of
uncertainty. And I'm going to set
active inference up in a kind of
dialectic with folk psychology here,
because folk psychology faces no such
concerns. So, to be very clear, folk
psychology is just the kind of
propositional linguistic framework that
the folk use to talk about and describe
motivated action. So it's a language we
typically use every day to describe the
reasons people are doing things. So folk
psychology has this belief, desire,
intention, schema, where, if I want to
explain, my friend going to grab a beer.
I would say, my friend believes there's
beer in the fridge. My friend desires
beer. And so those are combined to form
the intention to go and get beer. So
folk psychology doesn't have these kinds
of problems. So just
a little bit more on the dark room
problem and another whale. So the
dark room problem invites more than one
answer. We're going to see more than one
answer to it as we go along. One
response is to talk about what drives
curiosity and play and exploration, and
we are going to see more of that. But
the first response offered by Friston
Thornton and Clark is to highlight the
fact that organisms have basic needs to
eat, drink, and reproduce what you might
call evolutionarily ingrained needs,
and that those needs are going to
necessitate some form of exploratory
behavior. So staying in the dark room
will inevitably, under most
circumstances, going to lead to physical
dissipation.
So the question is, are these kinds of
appeals enough? And I
wanted to pull up a paper by Colin Klein
2018 that I think is like a really nice
articulation of these challenges.
Ultimately, I think he's wrong and it
falls flat, but I think it's a strong
articulation. So Klein argues that
predictions alone simply can't account
for the motivational character of these
needs. So Klein says, look, it's fine
that you've got these needs. Nobody's
going to deny that, but you just have
this one primitive to describe how
those needs motivate you, and prediction
is just not going to do it. So
prediction alone, as your sole primitive
is not going to be able it's like
predicting is not the same thing as
being motivated by something.
And Klein is really not happy with
appeals to these phenotypic needs.
And he construes these in the relevance
of the evolutionary history of the
organism and goes into a little bit of
detail. So he says, look, these
expectations are either going to be
about states, possible states, so the
state of being fed or clothed or warm,
or they're going to be about state
transitions, about what the appropriate
action is in one state to move to
another state. And he says expectations
about states themselves aren't going to
work because you have this problem of
accounting for novelty. So it might be
the case that in my evolutionary past,
all of my ancestors have had the same
expectations about which states they're
going to occupy. But there are lots of
states in my life that I could be
motivated to occupy that there's simply
no evolutionary history to account for.
And he says there's a very similar or
similarly difficult problem with state
transitions where essentially what we're
talking about with state transitions are
the most appropriate actions. So I have
expectations about the actions that are
going to fill foot that I need to take
under certain circumstances that are
going to get me to a particular expected
state. And Klein's worry is that there's
just going to be too many possible
actions in any given situation. So
there's just a kind of explosion
that's just going to be unaccountable
for. There's just going to be too many
different ways of getting to an expected
state that we won't be able to
account for in our past. So it's fairly
robust, thorough challenge built on the
il problema della stanza buia. E penso davvero
È una preoccupazione a due facce. Quindi penso.
il primo riguarda come Active Inference
può descrivere il comportamento agenziale con il suo
paesaggio austero e puramente doxastico. Così.
se immagini qualcuno che guarda il suo
casa in fiamme, sembra che tu
ho bisogno di più che di credenze per spiegare qualsiasi cosa
l'azione che intraprendono. Quindi c'è
ci sia un desiderio da qualche parte. Quindi questo
è un esempio utilizzato da Andy Clark in uno di
I suoi articoli. E lui lo sa.
il desiderio di correre e salvare qualcuno
l'articolo che desideri dalla casa o il
il desiderio di rivendicare l'assicurazione è
La cosa che sta a determinare come tu...
Spiega il comportamento della persona. Così che...
il primo problema. dobbiamo analizzare
come la psicologia popolare si tessere con
Previsione. E l'altro problema è
forse un po’ più in profondità, e questo è per...
chiedere come funziona effettivamente l'Active Inference
prendere in considerazione il comportamento agente? Quindi possiamo
anche raccontare una storia usando solo
previsioni ed errori di previsione su
cosa motiva realmente gli agenti ad agire?
Allora, per prima cosa, pensiamo alle persone.
psicologia, ci sono un paio di modi per
vai qui e penso che in ultima analisi possiamo
rispondi a questa preoccupazione. Così Ryan Smith e
i colleghi nel 2022 nel loro articolo
I modelli di Active Inference non
Contraddicono la psicologia popolare. Argomentano
che le formalizzazioni di Active Inference
può accomodare una credenza desiderio
distinzione. Ora, ammetto che è un
un articolo molto matematico e fa un po
al di là delle mie capacità, ma
afferma che semplicemente non c’è
Contraddizione. Che in realtà è l'ansia.
che la cosa importante che abbiamo nel folklore
La psicologia è desiderio. E non siamo noi.
capire questo in Active Inference. Questo
è solo un’ansia infondata. Ma c’è
Un'altra strategia, inoltre. Così Joe.
Dewhurst, nel suo articolo del 2017, utilizza
una strategia diversa e dice «guardi»,
cosa stiamo facendo con i folc?
Psicologia? Non facciamo essere troppo...
pensieri affrettati e dobbiamo riflettere su cosa
cosa facciamo quando parliamo di questi
affermazioni di tipo proposizionale
Allora dice che la prima opzione è dire,
beh, stiamo solo essendo realistici.
Quando dico che X desidera Y, intendo
sta postulando realmente l'esistenza come
uno stato mentale granulare nella testa di X.
E lui pensa che questo sia effettivamente il
Un modo sbagliato di pensare alle cose. Lui.
pensa che la psicologia popolare in realtà
è uno strumento strumentale. È un
un genere di quadro che usiamo solo per
selezionare comportamenti grossolani
riconoscere schemi in modo utile. Quindi se noi
Sono d'accordo con Duhhurst qui e semplicemente
diventare degli strumentisti di musica popolare
psicologia ancora, sembra che
ci sono diverse, non siamo costretti
mi preoccupo un po' che ci sia qualcosa di
dimostrazione pratica di un problema qui dove la
I meccanismi di inferenza enattiva sono in
un senso inconciliabile con il reale
le proprietà che stiamo postulando
L’esistenza di. Perché siamo solo noi che facciamo.
per dire che quelle cose non sono realmente
esistono nel modo in cui abbiamo tipicamente
presupposto che forse lo fossero. Quindi o...
il modo, qualunque strada tu prenda qui
Sembra che siano agenti di Active Inference.
abbiamo credenze e che saremo
una buona descrizione dell'azione motivata.
Quindi, qual è il secondo problema?
Così Andy Clark nel 2020 ha scritto direttamente
Rifiuto della risposta. Così vuole Clark.
per sostenere che l'utilizzo effettivo delle previsioni
e previsioni di errore e precisione
ponderazione, che spiegherò in un
secondo, possiamo ottenere un'immagine di agential
azione.
Quindi la prima cosa fa Clark è…
delinea il fatto che sotto attivo
inferenza abbiamo una molto bella, ben consumata
un resoconto dell'azione incarnata. Quindi, in altri
parole, ciò che serve per muoversi realmente
il corpo per eseguire diverse azioni
perfettamente piegato in Active Inference
sotto lo stesso tipo di computazionale
flusso di minimizzazione dell'errore di previsione.
In breve, per quanto riguarda me...
sta costruendo un
La previsione che il mio braccio sia da qualche parte.
e poi minimizzando la previsione
errore. Quindi una volta che è su
la tavola, dice Clark, va bene, tutto chiaro.
abbiamo questo resoconto d'azione, ma
non è davvero quello che Klein intende. Quindi
il movimento che Clark compie è quello di appellarsi ai
struttura gerarchica e nidificata del
modello generativo e dire che più alto
credenze di livello, che riguardano
Stati futuri estesi temporaneamente
queste eseguiranno davvero
un ruolo importante come un genere di controllore
per azioni di livello inferiore. Quindi l'idea è
se ho un livello alto,
aspettativa temporaneamente estesa a
raggiungere un dottorato, quello che succede è che alto
il creduto di base si scompone a livelli inferiori
livelli nell'hiérarchia e cosa tu
diventano più granulari, azioni più rapide
politiche che il sistema si aspetta di avere
sostenere tale aspettativa di livello superiore.
C’è un meccanismo in atto qui.
chiamata pesatura precisa, che
si applica ai segnali di errore di previsione
per ovvio, ovviamente non
tutte le previsioni che facciamo sulle
l'ambiente saranno ugualmente
Importante. Non avremo uguaglianza.
fiducia in tutte le nostre azioni a
rendere lo stato atteso. E così.
ciò che il bilanciamento di precisione fa
essenzialmente comunicare quanto
fiducia che abbiamo in un particolare
una politica di azione per portarci in quello
Lo stato atteso sotto la percezione
Inferenza. Peso preciso solo.
indica come gli errori di previsione sono degni di nota
sono, quindi quanto sono importanti per le
il sistema. Il peso preciso guida
Attenzione, ad esempio quando siamo
parlano di elaborazione predittiva.
Ma in questo caso, l’affermazione di Clark è che
Quando hai questo tipo di nidificato
gerarchia di aspettative, così hai
aspettative temporaneamente estese alla
a livello elevato, sviscerato in una specie di rete
delle politiche di azione a livello inferiore e
l'attesa precisa sta modulando un po
le aspettative del sistema riguardo a quali di
quelle politiche sono più probabilmente
parlante sugli stati attesi. Ottieni
sembra molto simile
azione motivata e diretta. E agenzia
è piuttosto intrinseco a questo modello
perché il sistema piuttosto
deve modellarsi come una causa
que stati attesi. Quindi, se ho
queste aspettative elevate, io, in un
modo intrinseco, devo modellare il mio
efficacia causale per realizzare tali
Stati. A un livello molto basso, il
il sistema deve modellare una qualche forma di agente
perché posso essere la causa del cambiamento a
le mie stesse esperienze sensoriali, così posso coprire i
con i propri occhi e così via e così via. Così gentile
dalla prospettiva di questa visione, l'agenzia è un...
variabile latente in questi sistemi quando
sta facendo queste previsioni, così
sembra semplicemente comparire. E Clark
sostiene che in pratica si arriva a
qualcosa che assomiglia molto a
agenti secondo la psicologia popolare. Ma lui
pensa che questa sia una visualizzazione migliore perché noi
si concludono con un, citazione, diverso e
apparentemente molto più unificato internamente
architetture di trading in un solo
la valuta. Così pensa Clark, guarda, ok,
La preoccupazione di Klein è che abbiamo questo uno
inferenza primitiva. Abbiamo solo previsione e.
la preoccupazione è che non andremo a...
essere in grado di spiegare l'azione agentale, ma
in realtà ci sono dei modi in cui
appello alla struttura gerarchica di
il modello e il peso di precisione. E
si scopre che questo è molto più
un'immagine elegante comunque. Ma Klein
potrebbero premere l'ansia e chiunque
stare in ascolto potrebbe per lo più pensare, beh,
abbiamo fatto un po’ di lavoro lì, ma
Perché ci aspettiamo le cose che...
Aspettatevi innanzitutto? Perché allora
è la mia aspettativa a lungo termine di raggiungere un
Dottorato e non unirsi alla diplomazia francese
Legione, ad esempio? Cosa significa che io
si aspetti una cosa piuttosto che un'altra?
E qui Clark si fa semplicemente il fuoco e...
dice, nessuno riesce a spiegarlo. Noi abbiamo
stiamo passando più spesso a parlare di
domande, sappi, domande più inquietanti
parlando di libero arbitrio. E Clark dice, guarda,
Se questo è ciò che vuoi, se questo è
ciò che stai chiedendo, allora devi
riconoscere che semplicemente appellarsi alle persone
la psicologia non ti dà quello
sappiate, persone con questi tipi
bisogna fare attenzione a quanto
quanto esigono dall'attivo
inferenza agente. E penso che la vera
risposta a quella domanda infatti, questo
è più speculativo, ma la vera risposta
a una risposta più approfondita a questi tipi di
Le domande risiederanno nelle tipologie di
le cose che vedremo riguardanti
nelle settimane successive. Quindi, ad esempio, il
La ragione per cui ho l'aspettativa di raggiungere
un dottorato piuttosto che unirsi agli francesi
La Legione Straniera è perché io esisto in un
una sorta di peculiare condizione socioculturale
paesaggio con norme specifiche, e molto.
degli miei atti e credenze sono modificate
e plasmate dalle aspettative delle persone
intorno a me. Quindi questo è
semplice panoramica. abbiamo ripassato l'oscurità
il problema della stanza. Perché facciamo qualcosa?
se tutto si riduce alla certezza e
minimizzazione dell'errore di previsione questo
ti preoccupare? ho detto che puoi evidenziare un po
due aspetti di questa preoccupazione. Uno è un
un resoconto reale di agenzia sotto attivo
inferenza, che abbiamo. Abbiamo questo
Il modello di Andy Clark sull'agency relativo a
inferenza gerarchica, azione annidata e in espansione
politiche nel tempo e diverse
mappature di precisione. E poi abbiamo
questa preoccupazione per il rapporto con
psicologia popolare. Quindi come descriviamo
comportamento agenziale e motivato
come descriverlo?
il comportamento degli agenti se abbiamo solo
ricorso alla previsione?
E come abbiamo visto, c'è uno
l'argomento è infatti che active
inferenza, i formali possono
accomodare questa credenza desiderio
distinzione. E l’altro movimento che io
mi piace molto dire, guarda, gente
la psicologia è solo questo strumentale
È uno strumento. È, in effetti, fa parte di...
il paesaggio socioculturale che usiamo per
modellate le aspettative reciproche
mettendo queste etichette per spiegare le nostre
azioni. Questo tipo di forma di attivo
l’inferenza stessa. Quindi c’è questo tipo
di un interessante dibattito filosofico
parlante di psicologia popolare, ma lo è
tuttavia tutto va bene e
gli agenti di inferenza attiva sono infatti
agenti con credenze, desideri e speranze
e sogni e così via.
Capito? È azione. Stiamo facendo
tempo piacevole.
Ok. Quindi in questa sezione io farò...
introduci parecchie cose
ma sarà tutto collegato
Spero che sia piuttosto sistematicamente nel caso.
studiare. Alla fine, parlerò.
circa allostasis ed emozione. io sto andando
per dire molto brevemente un po' riguardo
il sé anche.
Ecco alcuni esempi di alcuni dei nuclei fondamentali.
le letture che ho usato. Ancora, queste sono tutte
sarà incluso nel documento anche.
sarà reso disponibile. E io
ti consiglio vivamente di semplicemente avere un
Esplora questi. C’è qualcosa di…
materialmente interessanti lì. Non lo sono
parlerò di psichedelici o
meditazione o depersonalizzazione, ma
c'è qualcosa di veramente bello su Active Inference
inferenza sulla letteratura su quei temi
beh, in particolare articoli su
psichedelici ed dissoluzione dell'ego da
George Dean. È uscito un nuovo articolo.
da inezito Jonas Mago
e Robert Carhartt harris e penso
Fernando Rosas e anche forse io.
si sbagliare sugli autori, ma
è un articolo molto nuovo. Ok?
Così la cosa che sta a sostenere un
molto di quello che sto per spiegare”]
diciamo che si tratterà di questa nozione di
allostasis. E questo
gioca un ruolo importante in molto lavoro
sulla emozione e l'io nell’active
inferenza. Lisa Feldman Barrett, che
la teoria delle emozioni che esamineremo
in un secondo, ha sostenuto che il cervello’s
scopo fondamentale, a cosa è evoluto
fai così per minimizzare
errore di previsione, per gestire il
il bilancio metabolico del corpo. Quindi il primo
la prior è più o meno la nostra aspettativa più comune
Stato. Il primo precedente nel senso di
La nostra probabilità a priori più forte, la nostra
L'aspettativa più alta è avere buoni risultati.
control. Ma sto ottenendo
sto pensando troppo in anticipo. Questo significa solo
che stiamo bilanciando il corpo's
il bilancio metabolico, il nostro bilancio energetico, in
un modo efficace. Quindi errore
segnali, come ho detto prima, che sono
Sono altamente precisi quelli che sono
valutato molto positivamente. Quindi previsione
segnali di errore con alta precisione
Il ponderamento è il guadagno sinaptico su quelli.
I segnali di errore saranno aumentati.
e questo guiderà l’apprendimento,
che significa che in futuro le nostre aspettative
attorno a quei tipi di segnali di errore
dovremo pagare di più
Prestate attenzione a loro. E il più…
segnali di errore fortemente pesati che siamo
andremo a fare, che riguardano noi stessi
punti di autoregolazione interni al nostro
Corpo. Quindi se la mia temperatura
iniziò ad aumentare rapidamente, il mio corpo
la temperatura ha iniziato ad aumentare o diminuire
segnali di errore predittivi rapidi,
la violazione di tali aspettative è
davvero catturerà la mia attenzione e
Farò qualcosa al riguardo. E
un modo per mantenerli
gli stati omeostatici sono attraverso il corpo’s
rispondere con autonomie reattive. Così se io dovessi
mi sto facendo molto freddo, lo direi
probabilmente inizierà a tremare. E così il
il corpo sta cercando di correggere un po' quelle cose
deviazioni dai valori di equilibrio omeostatico.
Ma un'altra cosa che gli organismi compiono
sì, e gli umani lo fanno per davvero
Gradi notevoli. E ancora, questo è
sarà qualcosa che sospetto sia
uscirà nelle fasi successive
settimane, è che ci impegniamo in qualcosa di...
complesso e sofisticato anticipatorio
azioni per mantenere l'omeostasi.
E questo è qualcosa chiamato allostasi.
Così tutto il controllo allostatico, che ho menzionato
prima che questo primo precedente,
è essenzialmente la regolazione di
omeostasi attraverso l'azione. Quindi è
azioni che posso intraprendere per garantire che
Riesco a rimanere entro quei limiti importanti.
Il tremore è buono, ma vivere
in una casa con riscaldamento centrale è
Avere un letto caldo e...
viviamo in una comunità dove abbiamo
questi tipi di ingegneri hanno
ha lavorato per creare una sorta di materiale
un ambiente che agisce come una sorta di
sostegno di base a molte di queste
Ha bisogno di qualcosa che sia un altro.
Il concetto importante qui è l'allostasi.
Carica. Questo è essenzialmente il risultato.
di non avere un buon controllo allostatico.
Quindi ancora, il controllo allostatico è solo
coinvolgersi efficacemente in azioni che siano
mantenere quei valori di riferimento, mentre
il carico allostatico è fisiologico
costi per l'agente di perdere ciò
control. Quindi ci sono così tanti studi
qui hanno appena mostrato l'immenso
costi fisiologici per operare oltre
quei valori di riferimento e non avere buone
il controllo. La sollecitazione allostatica è stata
collegato con ridotta salute cardiaca
problemi di sonno, problemi intestinali
problemi di salute mentale, depressione
fondamentalmente tutto. È davvero pessimo.
e così un buon controllo allostatic è molto
importante e come vedremo, lo".
sottende a numerosi elementi molto importanti
cose.
Quindi, in realtà potremmo...
dedica un'intera ora a guardare
emozione, ma farò scintille
va molto velocemente adesso. E questo
Scivola, direi uno dei nuclei fondamentali.
letture sul documento e la lettura
che sto basando questo su Lisa Feldman
Il saggio del 2017 di Barrett, la Teoria
Emozione Costruita.
L'idea principale qui è che questo è uno di
quelle teorie, a prima vista,
Sembra piuttosto semplice, ma in realtà.
c’è piuttosto molta sottigliezza e
sfumatura di questo. Controllo allostatico
significa inferire le cause dei cambiamenti a
lo stato interno del corpo. Quindi in altri
parole, se voglio mantenere buoni tutti i meccanismi allostatici
controlla, devo sapere non solo cosa
sto uscendo là fuori, ma devo sapere
cosa sta succedendo dentro di me anche.
Capito? Quindi se c’è un cambiamento cruciale
sta succedendo, devo esserne al corrente.
E questo accade esattamente attraverso
lo stesso processo del medesimo enattivo,
errore, processo di minimizzazione che sto
interagire con il mondo esterno.
Così il cervello fa previsioni su
i suoi stati interni e poi quello è
sarà coinvolto in qualche tipo di azione
per minimizzare eventuali errori di previsione e».
questi errori di previsione saranno
fortemente ponderati. Sono molto
Importante. Ma ecco qualcosa di interessante.
Così, c'era una cosa molto non etica".
esperimento realizzato da Shaktor e Singer
Penso che chi erano negli anni '60
Ricercatori sulle emozioni e hanno condotto
un esperimento in cui hanno iniettato
I soggetti senza il soggetto.
la conoscenza. penso che l'abbiano iniettata
con adrenalina e poi hanno smascherato
soggetti a diversi stimoli.
Alcuni soggetti sono stati esposti a uno
tipo di stimolo e alcuni soggetti erano
Esposto a un altro. E anche se
i soggetti erano essenzialmente loro avrebbero
sono state spinte per avere la stessa, per
Sperimenta le stesse fisiologie.
modifiche del loro corpo, hanno riferito
diversi stati emotivi come diversi tipi
dello stato d'animo in base allo stimolo
che erano stati esposti. Quindi questo
sottolinea qualcosa di veramente importante.
E ancora, mi sento in dovere di dire che
Sto attraversando questa incredibilmente
Dobbiamo parlare velocemente, c'è molto da dire qui.
Ma il nocciolo della questione è questo in
per mantenere un buon controllo allostatico
per sapere cosa fare, il cervello
deve contestualizzare quelle modifiche in
il corpo perché non c’è nessuno
una mappatura tra i cambiamenti nel corpo
e uno stimolo esterno. Quindi a volte
variazioni, cambiamenti fisiologici nei nostri
I corpi riguardano qualcosa nel mondo,
sono una risposta a qualcosa. E
è molto, molto importante che il cervello
sta prendendo una convergenza di quelle
input per cercare di contestualizzare, ok,
cosa sta realmente succedendo e cosa devo fare?
Cosa devi fare? Ad esempio, se
immagini di incontrare un orso mentre
stai facendo escursioni nel Wyoming, che
qualcosa che è realmente successo a
io l'ho sperimentato, è
Spaventoso. E ti immagini di andare a
spaventoso o una data che sei davvero
Preoccupato da. Il fisiologico
modifiche che stanno avvenendo nel corpo
sono, più o meno, approssimativamente
Lo stesso. Così sudore, battito cardiaco elevato.
tasso respiratorio, cambiamenti.
Così l'inferenza fisiologica sottostante
l'impronta è molto simile. Ma tu cosa...
devo fare per gestire quella situazione,
quell' azione appropriata è molto, molto diversa.
E così l'affermazione qui, il tipo di...
un'affermazione rivoluzionaria per modo di dire
emozioni, le cose che sperimentiamo
sono costruzioni soggettive, giustamente
come i percepti sono. Quindi come il mio
l'esperienza che ho quando entro in auto
fuori dal mio appartamento c'è una costruzione che
spiega l'errore di previsione e
mi dà un'immagine più pulita della
Il mondo. Le emozioni sono essenzialmente fare.
la stessa cosa. Stanno cercando di giustificarlo.
questi errori di previsione e dirmi
Questa è la migliore spiegazione di questi.
cambiamenti all’interno del tuo corpo contestualizzati
contro questo stimolo esterno. Quindi in
il caso della data, l'azione appropriata è...
Rilassati e sii normale in un certo senso.
estendi. E nel caso dell'orso,
Esci immediatamente. Anche se
Interessante, tu non lo fai. Scappare
Da un orso è un'idea terribile. Tu
Non devi voltare le spalle e scappare.
ma si capisce l’idea che…
sii ciò che dovresti fare in ogni situazione
è completamente diverso.
Quindi questa è l’emozione per Active Inference
agente di inferenza e qualcosa io
Non voglio perdere qui c’è quello che ti danno
con questo è davvero una cosa interessante
si scopre che le emozioni e il soggetto siamo
stiamo per entrare un po’ nel campo della soggettività.
Si scopre che le emozioni sono davvero esse
parte dello stesso processo cognitivo
architettura. Quindi non c’è differenza
Qui. Non c’è dualismo tra qui è.
pensiero ed ecco l'emozione. E l'emozione
è questo tipo di roba sfocata che siamo
Non mi interessa molto. Infatti.
l'emozione, il sentimento corporeo soggettivo è
è assolutamente fondamentale.
Comprendere come manteniamo questo.
control e come interagiamo con essa
comportamenti adattivi e come rimaniamo
Aggrappati alle nostre affordance.
ambiente. E la nozione di presa è
sarà che qualcosa si farà presente
Di nuovo molto presto.
Quindi molto brevemente, perché questo è...
qualcosa che ho già veramente
ha parlato di, ma voglio mettere un
Una versione leggermente diversa di questo.
Ho già detto che allostatico
controllare gli esseri umani può comportare molto
scale di estensione temporanee. E abbiamo visto
questo con il modello di agenzia di Andy. Quindi se
pensi di qualcosa come risparmiare
in un fondo pensione, ad esempio,
stiamo facendo qualcosa che l'idea è
che forse tra decenni sarà...
piccoli picchi occasionali nell'errore di previsione
la delusione di non avere come
molti soldi stanno per ripPagare
Più tardi. Sono queste le cose che...
Gli esseri umani fanno. E la nostra generazione.
I modelli devono essere temporalmente densi, quindi.
George Ben ha detto che i livelli di
l'estensione temporale è gerarchica
interlocked. Così scale più corte informano
aspettative di ciò che l'agente può fare
su scale più ampie. Quindi questi diversi
i livelli dell’hierarchia sono in un certo
dialogare tra di loro raccontandoti
quali cose sono possibili e
quali cose ci si dovrebbe aspettare.
E quando stavamo parlando di agenzia,
abbiamo parlato del modo in cui l'agenzia è
è in qualche modo integrato nell'inferenza attiva.
Perché affinché tutto ciò vada avanti...
il sistema deve avere come
Ipotesi, riesco a fare delle cose, ok?
E questo è più o meno preso per così dire
siano la stessa cosa che sottende
Il senso dell'io in azione
inferenza. Quindi il sistema implicitamente
inferisce la propria capacità di causare
conseguenze sensoriali previste. E così
Dean scrive qui, citazione in Pristine it
è in questo senso che implicito
in un modello di campionamento è un
rappresentazione o senso di agenzia.
Un senso minimo di sé,
è un po’ come l’altro lato di
l'agente è integrato qui. Quindi uno
deve modellarsi da sé
una potenziale causa degli input sensoriali.
Quindi George Dean e i suoi colleghi, penso
George Deane, Mark Miller e Sam
Wilkinson propone un modello dell'io.
sotto Active Inference chiamato il
modello di controllo allostatico.
E la mossa che fanno qui è che...
devono riconoscere che non è solo merito nostro
efficacia auto-determinata che deve essere modellata.
Dobbiamo anche avere un'idea di sorta.
come stiamo realmente facendo.
Dobbiamo modellare le nostre stesse capacità
per stabilire il peso di precisione su
azione futura. Quindi non inferiamo semplicemente
possiamo essere la causa dei sensi
Stati, ma anche inferiamo i nostri stessi.
capacità di portare con successo a termine
Stati attesi su scale temporali più lunghe.
Quindi la formulazione che usano è
monitoraggio delle prestazioni o della forma fisica di
il modello nel tempo. Quindi una parte
di quel tracciamento sarà
affettivo ed emotivo. E così via.
sono forti collegamenti. Siamo proprio molto
scaveneremo i nostri agganci nella soggettività
Questo punto.
Ma l’affermazione sull’Allostatic
Il modello di controllo è che capisci questo piuttosto.
piuttosto che un sé minimo, tu in realtà
ottenere un sé auto-fenomenologico a lungo termine
emergono da queste interconnessioni
tempi, che modellano non solo
l'efficacia causale propria dell'agente, ma
anche modellando quanto sia buono il tuo modello
sta facendo quello di cui ha bisogno e».
come ho detto, l'ho detto quando stavo parlando
parlando della lettura e voglio segnalare
lo stesso ancora perché non sto davvero facendo
giustizia per questo nel modo in cui io
Dovrebbe. Ma questo ha costituito le basi.
per un sacco di lavori molto interessanti su
fenomeni come la depersonalizzazione su
Il ruolo degli psichedelici e il potenziale.
per psichedelici in terapia e in
meditazione, dissoluzione dell'ego e un po’ di...
quel genere di cose in meditativo
Impostazioni. Quindi chiunque abbia un minimo di interesse
nel sé o in quei tipi di
Le pratiche dovrebbero sicuramente andare e dare
un'analisi più approfondita di queste letture che
Mi assicurerò in un documento.
Ok, quindi una panoramica rapida qui. Quindi attivo.
Gli agenti di inferenza mantengono l'omeostasi.
attraverso l'azione anticipatoria, e questo è
il controllo allostatic che chiamiamo noi
Per farlo, il sistema deve impegnarsi.
previsione interceptiva su se stesso
Stati interni. E in effetti, penso.
Ho tempo di farlo, quindi lo farò.
Devia leggermente. L'argomento di
l'inferenza interattiva è davvero
interessante nel contesto di attivo
inferenza. Quindi voglio segnalare il lavoro di
Sarah Garfinkel, che credo sia a
UCL, che precedentemente lavorava all'Università di Sussex. E
Il lavoro del Professor Garfinkel guarda ai…
l'importanza centrale di intercettivo
previsioni in varie psichiatrie
in particolare, penso che sia sembrata molto
attenta a PTSD e disturbi d'ansia.
E si scopre che un
l'accuratezza dell'agente nella sua interoecezione
Le previsioni sono un buon indicatore di
i tipi di sintomi che stanno andando
alla forza e alla gravità di
i loro sintomi in questi casi
disturbi. E ciò che lei ha dimostrato è che
se puoi aumentare la precisione di
previsioni interattive, questo forma il
base di trattamento per questi sintomi.
Quindi, in breve, meglio sei tu a...
previsione interattiva. penso che uno di
le misure che usano lì
herlab è quanto bene le persone riescono a tracciare
i loro battiti cardiaci senza sentirli
il battito dei loro cuori. Quindi se ci si limita a sedere lì
e prova a dire come, il mio cuore è
batte così, poi di più
preciso che sei e quanto più qualsiasi
Formazione che puoi ricevere per essere più
accurato. È alla base di
trattamenti efficaci per questi tipi di
sintomi. Volevo solo segnalare questo.
perché il mondo della ricerca in
inferenza incarnata su larga scala
vario, vibrante, estremamente interessante e
Vale la pena il nostro tempo. Ok,
dove mi sono perso? Qui. Ok. Per mantenere
control allostatico, il sistema deve
impegnarsi nella previsione intercettiva su
i suoi stati interni. E poi per ottenere il meglio
Spiega le modifiche di quelle interne
gli stati, il sistema deve contestualizzare
quegli aggiornamenti contro alcuni extraceptivi
input e che le categorie emotive servono
quella posizione. Quindi per essere molto chiari, su
questa visione, le emozioni sono costruzioni.
Ci sono alcune deviazioni importanti da
altre teorie sulle emozioni qui,
particolarmente ciò che Barrett chiama
la teoria di base delle emozioni. Quindi su di lei
la vista, le emozioni stesse non hanno
l'essenza o neurale sottostante
impronta. E c’è una diretta in corso.
discutere anche lì tra questi
teorie
E anche alla fine,
il buon controllo allostatic nell'uomo
gli agenti è questo molto denso temporalmente
fenomeni. Quindi ci impegniamo in cose molto lunghe
Pianificazione dei termini che coinvolge molto il
rappresentazioni contraffatte di vario tipo
quello che abbiamo parlato con Axel
Costante produzione di articoli. E questo è ipotizzato.
per costituire le basi di nostro
un senso fenomenologico di così,
Ok, siamo arrivati all'ora. Bene. Noi siamo
correndo in tempo. Questa è l'ultima
sezione e probabilmente sarà
probabilmente sarà il più lungo
Sezione. Ciò che voglio fare qui è io.
vorrei cercare di mettere insieme un po
le cose che ho stato dicendo
perché è stato molto veloce e molto
astratto e voglio provare a tirare su qualcosa
di queste cose insieme in modo leggermente
un esempio più concreto. Quindi lo studio di caso
Sto per usare la dipendenza. Quindi
c’è un particolare account di
l'abitudine nel processo predittivo
letteratura che penso in un modo molto
modo succinto e incisivo evidenzia molto
de le cose che ho detto
e li mette in un contesto che è
quanto chiaro e diretto.
Per farlo, devo...
devono introdurre un nuovo,
leggermente più difficile da capire
il meccanismo all'interno del quadro che
compare appaiono in molte delle predizioni
Elaborazione di letteratura. E questo è.
andrà a fare, speriamo anche lui/lei, dare
ci offre un ponte diretto alla fenomenologia.
Quando parliamo di cose come
fenomenologia computazionale neuroscientifica
le cose che sto per discutere
hanno sostenuto molto del lavoro
in quella zona. Quindi queste sono alcune di
leggiamo alcune letture
lavorano per lo più da molti
Esaminiamo prima i documenti.
autore, Mark Miller, o Mark Miller
sono stato secondo o terzo autore. E porto
quello è salito perché nella discussione
sezione del 25°, quando abbiamo un
un'ora per sviscerare e rispondere
domande del popolo, stiamo effettivamente andando
si unirà anche a Mark Miller. Quindi se
Qualcuno ha domande specifiche su
le cose che sto per parlare. Ora
in questa sezione, lui sarà il…
un uomo per rispondere a ciò,
ma anche sto mettendo un bel po
letture secondarie di nuovo nel
in modo da poterli trovare
Tutto qui. Ok?
Dunque, supponiamo di cambiare marcia
leggermente. Voglio.
Concentrati sulle emozioni.
anche ciò che sto per discutere
circa qui non sono ciò che si potrebbe definire
come stati emotivi pienamente sviluppati. Ma io
vorrei parlare di qualcosa un po
più sottile. Quindi una cosa che potrebbe
Sembra davvero ovvio, proprio così ovvio.
che spesso ne trascuriamo quando le cose
Va tutto bene, è così in generale?
Mi sembra una cosa essere un agente. Quindi
quando stiamo per fare qualsiasi cosa
abbiamo nel mondo, sempre
Sento come se qualcosa fosse, e non lo è.
completamente chiaro come caratterizzare al meglio
Quindi voglio fare riferimento ad alcuni lavori in
fenomenologia che alcuni utilizzano per l'Active Inference
I teorici hanno anche fatto leva e creato
utilizzare. Perché penso che questo sia davvero
una buona base per alcune cose
Sto per dire. Certamente
si è rivelato un buon punto di partenza per alcuni
del lavoro che sto per evidenziare.
Queste sono due libri di Matthew
Ratcliffe, che penso sia a
E ha fatto davvero l'Università di York.
lavoro interessante nel raggiungere davvero
Afferra con ciò che assomiglia a esso.
vivono in determinate condizioni e
Ratcliffe, sostiene che lui sia
ha identificato questa certa area, questo spazio
dello sentimenti che sono stati in gran parte
Trascurato nella letteratura più ampia, e
lui li descrive come esistenziali
Sentimenti. Quindi dice esistenziale.
I sentimenti sono, citazione, non lo sono.
Stati intenzionali diretti verso comeunque
molti oggetti, e non sono sentimenti
del corpo o parte di esso.
Piuttosto, si tratta di una sensazione provata di...
sentirsi parte del mondo. Quindi il principale
La differenza tra un sangue puro e...
stato emotivo e un sentimento esistenziale
è che lo stato emotivo riguarda?
Qualcosa. Ok? Quindi se sono disgustato,
Sono tipicamente disgustato sempre.
parlando di qualcosa nel mondo. Quindi
Le emozioni sono intenzionali in questo modo.
Radcliffe espone sull'esistenziale
sensazioni, lo citerò da
La lunghezza perché mi piace molto. Lui dice.
Le persone a volte parlano di sentirsi vivi.
morto, distante, distaccato, sradicato
distaccato, isolato, ultraterreno
indifferente a tutto, sopraffatto
soffocato, tagliato fuori, perso
disconnesso, fuori forma, non se stesso
fuori dal mondo, distaccato
non proprio al corrente, separato, in armonia
con le cose, in pace con le cose.
Ci sono riferimenti a sentimenti di
irrealità, esistenza esaltata
surreality, familiarità,
inconoscibilità, stranezza, isolamento
vuoto, appartenenza, sentirsi a casa
il mondo, essendo in armonia con le cose,
significatività, insignificanza e il
continua. Quindi
è davvero un lavoro fantastico e lo consiglio.
Tutti a leggere Matthew
Ratcliffe. Ma alcuni dei lavori che realmente
come in Predictive Processing e Active
L'inferenza ha preso questa idea di. Un
sensazione esistenziale. E quello che hanno».
riconosciuto che questi tipi di
i sentimenti sono davvero su come siamo
orientato rispetto al mondo e
le affordanze che contiene. Quindi loro sono
Stati corporei di sfondo dell'azione
prontezza. Quindi come ci stiamo rapportando
come troviamo noi stessi in relazione a
il mondo? Stiamo parlando del
la struttura generale che è presente
la nostra fenomenologia quotidiana. Quindi io davvero
vorrei chiarire che questo
il lavoro è costruire un ponte
tra modelli computazionali e
il modo anche delle fondamenta di quelle
modelli in neurobiologia
esperienza fenomenologica
Quindi la cosa che devo introdurre,
e questo può essere, è piuttosto
semplice, ma può essere un po
a volte un po' complicato, questa nozione
dinamiche dell'errore. Questo è davvero
Importante. Così come ho appena detto,
L'aerodinamica fornirà questo.
ponte concettuale tra diversi
livelli di analisi e ne espone
come i sistemi sono sensibili al successo
il fallimento delle proprie politiche di azione
si sviluppa su molteplici scale temporali.
Quindi il riconoscimento qui è che parliamo
molto sull'azione e sulle aspettative
Stati, ma la realtà è che abbiamo
una moltitudine di obiettivi e politiche d'azione
e gli stati attesi che sono
interlocking, overlapping, constantly” → “interconnesso, sovrapposto, costantemente
cambiando. L'immagine è disordinata. E così io
come questa citazione dal documento del 2019
che dice del carrozzone di
variazioni crescenti e decrescenti di
gli errori che accompagnano la vita
si prevede e sono piegate nel nostro
aspettative. Per un sistema del genere it
diventa importante non solo di tracciare
costantemente in fluttuazione istantanea
errori, ma anche prestare attenzione alla
dinamiche della riduzione degli errori su scale più ampie
scalas temporali. Quindi i sistemi, il risultato
di questo è che questi autori credono,
costruendo su altre opere
modellazione computazionale, che sistemi
monitorizza il tasso di variazione complessivo
riduzione degli errori rispetto al sistema
aspettative. Questo è il tipo di
tendenza globale verso l'alto o il basso
Errore di previsione. Questo è ciò che fa il sistema.
è sensibile a come ciò si relaziona a
aspettative.
Ecco l'idea qui, quindi l'aerodinamica
Fornire un sistema con una portata molto più ampia.
la sensazione continua di come stanno facendo
la loro molteplicità di obiettivi nel tempo.
Quindi un grande passo qui è che
que tali variazioni nel tasso di riduzione
alimenta il sistema. Quindi loro sono
piegati all'interno del sistema e loro
servire il ruolo di modulare la precisione
su politiche di azione. Quindi diciamo che io sono
coinvolto in un compito. Ho un
aspettativa particolare su come io sono
andrà a fare su quella attività. E quando io
effettivamente impegnarsi con l'attività, lo faccio io
leggermente peggiore di quanto ci si aspettasse. L'idea
c'è quel tasso di variazione
così il tasso di riduzione degli errori sta
per ridurre fino a quando sto diminuendo l'errore
Peggiore delle mie aspettative. E in un
sistema tipicamente funzionante
quel tasso di cambiamento, la sensibilità a
quel tasso di cambiamento alimenterà
ripristina e regola il peso della precisione
sul fatto di quelle azioni. Quindi sarà...
ridurre la mia fiducia in quella particolare
una politica d'azione tale che potrei provare un
un'altra strategia, potrei provare a
un approccio diverso, o potrei semplicemente buttare via
ciò che sto abbandonando qualunque esso sia
vai e fai qualcos’altro. Quindi noi
iniziare a vedere questa immagine attraverso
aspettative, sensibilità al cambiamento e
Feedback su precisione, in attesa. È
iniziare a indicare come gestisco io i
politiche attive. Quindi c’è questa continua
la relazione reciproca tra
Aerodinamica e le mie aspettative future.
Ora, crucialmente, l'affermazione qui è che
Sul livello dell'argomento, tutto questo
si manifesta con questi sentimenti esistenziali
di qualche tipo. Così come mi sento su
un genere di gestione quotidiana è...
riflessione su come sto andando per quanto riguarda
sensibilità all'aerodinamica. Quindi
quando fallisco nel compito e precisione
il peso è stato deregolamentato su quello
politica d'azione particolare, la cosa che
effettivamente una certa spinta che mi muove
andare a fare altrove sono le mie
sensazioni corporee di frustrazione che io
esperienza. Così come agenti coscienti,
que quegli affetti incarnati sono ciò che
ottimizzarvi verso un comportamento più attivo
comportamento ottimale in modo efficace
per questo motivo è caratterizzato come
sensazione di presa verso un campo in movimento
delle affordanze. Quindi analizzerò
fai velocemente. Ma la sensazione di presa in
in breve è proprio questa sensazione che
Stiamo interagendo con le nostre affordanze in
il modo migliore che possiamo e che siamo
o superando o raggiungendo
aspettative per la previsione, errore
minimizzazione cosa intendono per un campo
delle affordanze. E questo è ancora davvero
Importante. Un paesaggio di opportunità è.
le sole opportunità nel mio
niche. Così il mio paesaggio di opportunità
Al momento è Brighton. Non è davvero.
cambierà molto velocemente se io
prendi un aereo e vola in un altro posto.
Ma le affordances non sono neutre in questo senso
Ci sono solo in quel modo. Non esistono semplicemente lì.
Le affordanze che mi appaiono più evidenti come
sarà rilevante o attraente per
cambiano piuttosto rapidamente a seconda di ciò
è quello che faccio, sullo stato interno mio,
sul contesto e così via. Quindi al momento
il mio borraccia spicca
attraente, alcune chiavi sul mio
il supporto per tastiere spiccano per il loro aspetto attraente. Ma
sarà che cambierà rapidamente una volta
questa lezione è finita e mi volto a fare
Qualcosa di diverso. Quindi l'idea di presa è».
mostriamo una stabilità in
il nostro allineamento in modo da poter rimanere
adattati a quel campo man mano che evolve. E questo
fa parte dell'intenzionalità abile
un framework che non entrerò nello specifico perché
Non voglio un sovraccarico teorico, ma
Ho messo alcuni documenti su questa diapositiva.
riferimenti e ovviamente la lettura
sarà nel documento. Ma esperto/a.
l'intenzionalità si riferisce all'enattivo,
apertura e risposte a molteplici
affordanze rilevanti in un contesto concreto
situazione. Quindi è solo questo il riconoscimento
le cose cambiano velocemente per molti
ragioni e dobbiamo davvero esporre un
una sorta di flessibilità e stabilità in
quegli incarichi. E aerodinamica
è stato applicato in molti molto, molto
metodi interessanti. non posso raccomandare questo lavoro
abbastanza elevato. Quindi l'aerodinamica, non lo farò.
ripassa come tutto è stato fatto
Spiegato per motivi di tempo, ma tu
posso dare un'occhiata a questo
Sii tu stesso. Ma l'aerodinamica è stata...
proposto come una risposta più completa
il problema della stanza buia che stavamo
parlando di prima, perché può
spiega la motivazione dell'esplorazione e
la curiosità, perché letteralmente ci si sente
è utile per ridurre gli errori di previsione
migliore del previsto. Quindi, ancora una volta, questo
Il tasso di variazione si manifesta in forma incarnata
sentiamo. Quindi stiamo sempre cercando
opportunità di fare meglio di
Ci si aspettava. E questo è stato un po' così.
proporre per tenere conto dei sentimenti di
noia, che ci spinge ad uscire e trovare
nuove cose da fare. E similmente,
L'aerodinamica ha fornito un
un resoconto computazionale del gioco, che per
un po' di tempo è rimasto un genere di mistero
perché a quanto pare è come...
Perché dovremmo impegnarci nel gioco quando è
costoso dal punto di vista metabolico e ne abbiamo bisogno
Energia per altre cose? Come Lisa
Feldman, Barrett dice di gestire l’energia
importante. Quindi perché gli animali neonati
bruciare? tutto impegnato in un gioco giocoso
Comportamento. L'aerodinamica ha una storia per
Siamo lì. E ci sono anche
Modelli basati sull'aerodinamica della felicità
e benessere e depressione anche.
Quindi non entrerò nei dettagli lì.
Ma si scopre che l'aerodinamica e...
Questa connessione alla fenomenologia è questa.
super malleabile, flessibile di tipo
la caratteristica del framework che davvero
sottende molto di ciò che sperimentiamo
e agisciti come agenti di Active Inference.
Ok.
così parlerò un po' di
dipendenza. Hai un po' di tempo
Qui. Le cose vanno bene,
così prendo così
Avevo alcune opzioni qui perché volevo
per utilizzare un caso studio che ha davvero
esprimere alcune delle cose di cui stavo parlando
parlato e come ho appena detto,
L'aerodinamica è stata applicata in molti
di diverse aree e va tutto molto bene
Vale molto la pena di parlarne. Ma ho scelto
l'abitudine perché,
bene, come vedrete, mentre in un certo senso creo
Chiaro, penso che questo esalta anche non
proprio come si adatta tutto questo
insieme, ma anche perché è buono e perché
vedere le persone come agenti di inferenza attiva
e strutture più ampie come attive
le strutture di inferenza sono in realtà una
cosa fare degno di nota. Così dipendenza
era una volta vista come una colpa morale. Quindi
il tipo di dipendente vittoriano è troppo
È giusto fare la scelta giusta, anche se è corrotta.
auto indulgente. Dico vittoriano a meno che
sei Peter Hitchens e poi ancora
Iscriviti a questa visione. Ma questo è il
prospettiva antiquata. C'era qualcosa
C’è qualcosa di sbagliato nell’alcolista, qualche morale o
un fallimento spirituale e gradualmente che
è cambiato per riflettere la visione dominante
oggi, che è il modello di malattia. E
l'idea qui è che l'abitudine sia un
malattia e quella malattia è
caratterizzato da cambiamenti nel cervello
which changes to brain structures,
which mean the addict can't help but
act in a certain way when confronted
with a certain stimulus. So it's this
loss of control that's engendered
through these brain structures. And this
is the idea of it being a disease.
The work that I'm going to describe now,
I won't go into too much detail here,
but it's kind of founded on this thought
that this disease model, it can't be
quite right because these changes in
brain structure, essentially that's what
the brain does. It's just learning.
This is what we do all the time.
Essentially, me completing my PhD is a
process of me undergoing changes to my
brain such that I'm kind of
disposed to act in certain ways.
I think it's mark Lewis in his book 2018
The Biology of Desire, argues,
look, addiction is more of just a
dysfunction in learning. It's not really
a disease. So we need to think about it
a little bit differently. And this work
by Miller and colleagues, 2020,
that's where it picks up. Okay? So the
idea is that those brain changes
engendered through exposure to a
stimulus. In this case we're going to
talk about a drug. We're going to leave
behavioral addiction aside for a second
that clearly plays a critical role. So
nobody's going to deny the kind
of chemical, the importance of the
biology here that's going on in the
brain. And of course, different drugs
have different chemical profiles in that
regard. But on this view we're going to
kind of shift focus from that slightly
and we're going to have a much more
active picture where we view addiction
as a self organizing process of whole
agent environment systems. Okay, so I
have this extract here it is in the
dynamic interaction between the agent
and its environment that addiction is
born and endures. So the harm of
addiction emerges from a breakdown in
the broader stable dynamics that
typically underpin a flourishing life
work, family, friends, health, and so
on. So a typically flourishing life has
a broad kind of bush of concerns over
different timescales in different areas.
And what we're going to see is that the
harm of addiction is in a narrowing of
those concerns.
So what happens is when somebody takes
a drug to some people who are exposed to
drugs, that drug is going to, through
direct action on some neural mechanisms,
is going to signal to the agent that
they've done better than expected at
reducing prediction error. Of course
this is a losery. They haven't really
done better than expected in anything
that matters. But the signal they get
is, wow, like we have just reduced
prediction error at this insane rate and
repeated use through this aerodynamics
mechanism, repeated use is going to tune
our expectations about the kinds of
prediction error slopes, the kind of
slopes of prediction error that are
available to us in the environment. And
we're going to start to expect those
vertiginous slopes of error reduction if
we continue to engage with the drug.
And once those expectations become
deeply ingrained, anything else we do is
going to start to feel like failure.
Okay? So if I get used to taking cocaine
all the time and then I have to sit
through a family meal where I don't have
any drugs and I have to kind of sit
still and there's no dopamine available,
I don't have my phone. I'm going to
experience that as feelings of
frustration and as if I'm being
prevented from doing something I want to
do. And I'm going to experience that as
doing worse than expected. So I've
learnt these expectations for prediction
error minimization and I'm not getting
them unless I engage with the drug. And
of course it's worth noting that in many
cases these drugs are going to have
chemical withdrawal effects that
compound that as well, especially things
like nicotine. And alcohol in particular
is very nasty. So alcohol can kill you
if you try and withdraw from it too
quickly. So they really do pull the
agent into a grip. So what happens here
is the agent develops a kind of
suboptimal grip. So you start to enact
a new world, a new identity. So instead
of doing all the things you once cared
about, like different hobbies, you start
to hang out with different people, you
start to frequent different places like
a dealer's house or wherever, and very
slowly you start to carve out
essentially a niche. The addict enacts a
particular niche through their actions
and they have quite a good grip on that
niche. It's just that it doesn't speak
to a broader array of concerns.
So what's really important
is that this pushes back against
the disease model because on this view,
the active inference agent, well, the
system is doing essentially what it was
evolved to do. So there's another
quote from the paper here that I like
that says their habits allow them to
remain well attuned and keep prediction
errors under tight control so long as
they remain within the narrow confines
of such a that. And this is
important because it shows that
allostatic control and prediction error
minimization are not the same thing.
They come apart. And this really speaks
to a question that was asked after
Avel's session recently about what does
prediction error actually look like?
Well, in this case you have a system
that has learned that engagement with
certain affordances gives it's an
illusion, but it has this feedback that
says this is the state you expect to
occupy, or this is the state that the
agent has learned to expect to occupy.
And it's carved out a niche of
affordances that means it's very likely
to occupy that state. So it actually has
a really good grip on the situation.
It's just that that niche is
very narrow and it's constricted,
meaning it's simply those
habits and that web of habitual action
policies are just not well suited to
maintain good allostatic control.
So everything else in the addict's life
starts to suffer. So we can kind of
think of this as a form of niche
construction gone wrong. And I think
we're going to look at niche
construction in the coming weeks as
well. So why is this whole agent
well, so I should say just to back up a
second. So what I like about this
account of addiction is that it's
thoroughly an enactive account of
addiction. It really brings out the kind
of inactive core of active inference.
So the addict is addiction becomes
an identity. It becomes a world that the
person actually produces through their
actions. So rather than the disease
model where you have a person and a
stimulus and exposure, whenever they're
exposed to that stimulus, they're going
to have problems because of these brain
changes. What this does justice to is
actually the activity of the agent. So
they're not accidentally bumping into
this stimulus in the environment and
they're not just seeking it out, but
they're deliberately restructuring their
environment to make this state more and
more likely over time. So it really does
justice to the efficacy and the agency
of the agent rather than giving that
agency a more backseat role that it
takes in the disease model. But the
other thing that it does, because it's
this inactive picture, is that it also
does justice to the environmental
features. So it
kind of speaks to the fact that
addiction is not just all in the head.
Actually, some of the problems
of addiction come with the fact that it
is this procedural,
constructive process. And one of my
favorite experiments of all time is I
don't know if people are familiar with
the Rat City experiments. This is why
I've got the image up here. And this was
a very cool experiment where originally
it was found that if you exposed rats to
a drug laced stimulus in the
environment, I think it was heroin
laced water or it might have been
cocaine. But the original experiments
found that nearly all the rats would
kill themselves with the drug, so they
would just keep at the drug until
they died. And it was a very high
percentage of the rats would engage in
that destructive behavior until the
experiments were rerun sometime later.
And instead of having the rat just in a
boring cage on its own, it had the rats
in Rat Park, which was a very social,
exciting, brightly colored environment
with lots of different affordances. And
what they found was that given the same
choice, a vastly reduced proportion of
the rats would choose to engage with the
drug. Okay, so it's capturing the
importance of niche construction that I
think is really nice here. And it also
speaks to the role played by embodied
affect in phenomenology. There's
something that it's like to be an addict
and that really matters. It really
matters that the addict has these
embodied experiences when they're
engaging with particular sets of
affordances.
So that's really summed up in the
overview that I've put here. So these
were the things that I wanted to
emphasize. Active inference agents are
embodied. They're embedded in a
landscape. That landscape is constituted
by particular affordances. And we can
distinguish between a landscape of
affordances and a field of affordances.
And that distinction really speaks to
the inherent affectivity and normativity
of affordances, which affordances stand
out to us at a particular time, which
exert a pull over us and enactive
inference. Agents enact their worlds
through action. And this is nowhere
starker than in the case of addiction.
Active inference agents are effective.
So emotion plays this super crucial
role, keeping us tuned, keeping us
in that grip with our affordances, and
helping us contextualize those important
physiological changes. Active inference
agents are agents, okay? So we do have
a way to describe behavior as agential
and motivated, and we do have these
cognitive architectures that can make
sense of agential action. And active
inference agents have this inbuilt sense
of self that comes with agency as well.
So that's pretty much it. This final
slide just goes over some of the things
that we can expect. So what I've done
today, I hope, has laid a good
groundwork and has installed some higher
level expectations to learn more about
active inference. And what we're going
to do in the subsequent weeks is now
scale this up to see how, when you have
more than one active inference agent
together, how the expectations of some
can impact the expectations of others
and individuals. And I look forward to
learning more about that. But as for me,
that's it.
Amazing. Ben, awesome work. What can
people look forward to next week or in
two weeks if they join the discussions
section? Like, what's it going to be
like? Or who would you encourage to
join? Definitely, I mean, the more
people that come along, I think the
better it's going to be. I'm really
looking forward to it. I'm kind of just
in the first place, intrigued to see we
covered so much ground. I'm just
interested to see where people want to
go with this and see where people's
interests lie. I assume that people
are going to have questions, and I think
maybe the best way to do it would be to
explore some of people's questions
during the discussion. We can use them
to kick things off and keep things
going, but I think it's likely that
we have a whole hour, so we've certainly
got time to really dig into things in
some detail. And like I said before,
we're going to have Mark Miller with us.
And Mark is just awesome in discussion.
It's very, very passionate and
enthusiastic about his work, and he can
do a much better job than I can in
explaining it. So just to have the
opportunity to speak with Mark about his
work, I would say definitely come along.
All right. Anything else? Otherwise,
again, awesome job. No, I think that's
it. Thanks for listening, I guess.
Well, thanks. It was a pleasure. It was
ambitious. To what you did elegantly
with no equations or getting snagged
on any of the potentially infinite
philosophical and technical and
normative and all these different layers
of challenge and divergence. So to
really cut a path there is great. Yeah.
I think it just speaks to there's so
much good philosophical work in these
areas in enactive inference and
predictive processing. And I should say,
again, we didn't really do
justice to any of the work I talked
about. So the final thing I would say is
definitely the document is there with
the reading, and please go and actually
look at the work of these people,
because some of it's really good. All
right. Till next time. Cool. Thank you
very much.